James Gross NLRB Files /4057
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series IV. RELATED COMMITTEES
  - Sub-Series B. DIES (Martin) COMMITTEE RECORDS 1938-1940
    - Sub-Series 2. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1939-1940 (Box 9, Folder 26)
        relating to Washington Friends of Spanish Democracy; program of the Spanish refugee relief campaign; American League for Peace and Democracy; list of NLRB members belonging to the American League for Peace and Democracy.
    - Sub-Series 3. REPRINTS
      - Reprints, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 27)
        Nov-38
  - Sub-Series C. BURKE (Edward R.) COMMITTEE RECORDS 1939-1941
    - Sub-Series 1. CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1939-1941 (Box 9, Folder 28)
        Correspondence between Madden and Senator Edward R. Burke (15pp); between Saposs and Burke; substantial correspondence relating to Small Business Men's Petitions; Dean Acheson (Chairman for the Committee on Administrative Procedure Dept. of Justice) to the Attorney General discussing hearings (11pp); Burke to Millis.
    - Sub-Series 2. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 9, Folder 29)
        Undated; concerning Small Business Men's Petitions; general statements of Senator Burke (25pp+); Madden's statement on S. Res. 207; NLRB's reply to the check list inquiry of the Attorney General's Committee on Administrative Procedure (94pp).
  - Sub-Series D. SMITH (Howard, M.) COMMITTEE RECORDS 1937-1970
    - Sub-Series 1. CORRESPONDENCE
      - Correspondence, 1937-1939 (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Correspondence relating to the Jones and Laughlin Steel Corp. between Edmund M. Toland (General Counsel, Special Committee to Investigate the NLRB), Edwin S. Smith and Adolphus Andrews (Acting Secretary of the Navy); amendments to the Act; Committee organization and procedure; preliminaries including John A. Lapp interview, examination of review attorneys, questionnaire (11pp); compliance in the Connor Lumber & Land Co. and the Reconstruction Finance Corp. (RFC) withholding funds; A.C. Shiffler on James M. Miller and Thomas S. Hinkel regarding their availability as witnesses; unfair labor practices and rights of employees; summary and analysis of elections (20pp); summary of investigation (7pp); LaFollette Committee files (14pp); Charles Fahy correspondence concerning NLRB members as witnesses and supporting documents.
      - Correspondence, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 2)
        Correspondence concerning review attorneys; amendments to the Act; government contracts and RFC withholding payment; discussion of exhibits 580, 581 (17pp); letters to the editors of the New York Times and Newsweek; Mapes Davidson red baits Saposs and blasts Frank Bloom; charges that the Board violated the secrecy of income tax returns; Toland finds no evidence that the Board destroyed their files; analysis of Smith Committee amendments the the NLRA by J.T. Taft (attorney) (13pp), and William Green's analysis (8pp); Toland, Fahy correspondence regarding the Sterling Electric Co. case; Hyacinthe Ringrose red baits Marie Prince; Toland's resignation from the Smith Committee; Kennedy Home Farm file (4pp).
      - Correspondence, 1941-1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
        Correspondence relating to former trial examiner Thomas Hart Kennedy and the Columbia Box Board Mills case and George Pratt (25pp+); Blakenhorn to Howard W. Smith (Chairman, Special Committee to Investigate the NLRB) about blacklisting (4pp).
      - Correspondence (Box 10, Folder 4)
        Undated; P. Ballantine and Sons, and Wholesale Liscensed Alcoholic Beverage Salesmen's Union #20376-B.
    - Sub-Series 2. REPORTS AND OFFICIAL DOCUMENTS
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1937-1939 (Box 10, Folder 5)
        relating to the anti-independent union attitude of the Board; El Popular; Madden's statement on S.1970 (17pp); examination of review attorneys' files; affidavits from Robert A. Muir, George D. McKay and Robert Davies denying affiliation with the Communist Party; Howard W. Smith's speeches on the NLRA and the Board; Judge Smith's visit to the White House.
      - Reports and Official Documents, 1940-1958 (Box 10, Folder 6)
        concerning Blakenhorn; Mapes Davidson's statement on communist activities (15pp); anonymous FBI reports on the misuse of congressional appropriations, internal security, and security matter; John C. Shover; minority report from A. Guy Hope (25pp+); special supplement Labor Relations Reporter, "Report on the Investigation of the NLRB" (53pp); reply from David Saposs to charges in final (majority) report (8pp); and Dept. of Justice report on Nathan Witt before the House Committee on Un-American Activities
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 10, Folder 7)
        Undated; pertaining to the presentation of 35,000 documents as evidence; criticism of the Committee's use of documents, as well as its selection of witnesses and questionnaire responses; Hawaiian investigation; list of articles from Howard Smith's scrapbook; reports on the St. Louis, Cincinnati, and Los Angeles offices; incompetence of staff; Blakenhorn; ambiguous testimony by Charles Fahy; inter-organizational criticism; closed shop agreement with the NLRB Union; propaganda trips of Elinore Herrick; free speech; legislative activities; report on A.L. Wirin referring to his defense of communists; American Trade Unionism and the Roosevelt Regime by H.A. Marquand (15pp); explanation of proposed draft (15pp); Witt files; reference to Leiserson and the John R. Commons letter; exhibits 25B, 32 for red baiting Mary Van Kleeck; analysis of Senator Wagner's defense of the Act and its administration.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 10, Folder 8)
        Undated; relating to analysis of the Republican Program Committee's report on the NLRB (29pp); Donald Wakefield Smith's statement on proposed amendments to the NLRA (32pp); report on Jack Davis (trial examiner, Philadelphia office); hearing excerpts; resume of testimony concerning blacklisting from J. H. Brock (17pp); The Smith Committee Amendments (H.R. 9195) (15pp); objection to 35,000 documents; summary of questionnaire responses (45pp); explanation of amendments recommended (13pp); biographical report on Nathan Witt; notes on the files of Edwin S. Smith.
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 10, Folder 9)
        Undated; concerning a survey of the work of the Board (16pp); summary of conclusions (34pp); conduct of the investigation by committee counsel; analysis of the record, file II (50pp+); the trial examiner's division (26pp); analysis of majority report (40pp+).
      - Reports and Official Documents (Box 10, Folder 10)
        Undated; pertaining to other criticisms of the Board's administration of the Act (15pp); the functioning of various board divisions (35pp+); the review section (30pp); administrative practices of board members (45pp+); allegations of partisanship (30pp+); the Boards interpretation of the Act (13pp); performance of duties by Board employees (25pp).
    - Sub-Series 3. TESTIMONIES [1939]-40
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 11)
        Barclay, Hartley W. (writer and editor, New York, NY); Barrow, Roscoe L. (Attorney, Review Section, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Blair, Harry W. (attorney, Alexandria, VA); Blakenhorn, Herber (Special Investigator, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 12)
        Bloom, Frank (Assistant Chief Trial Examiner, NLRB Washington, D.C.); Bokat, George (Trial Examiner, NLRB, Silver Spring, MD); Boyls, Fannie M. (Review Attorney, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Bradley, Charles A. (Assistant Chief of Mail and Files Division, NLRB, Greenbelt, MD); Brooks, George R. (Assistant Director of the Technical Service Division, NLRB, Arlington, VA)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 13)
        Condon, Robert L. (Attorney, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Cowdrill, Robert H. (Regional Director, 11th Region, NLRB, Indianapolis, IND); Cuevas, Marina (Hispanic Foundation of the Library of Congress, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 14)
        Davidson, Mapes (former Trial Examiner, NLRB, Orange, NJ)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 15)
        Davis, Jack (Attorney, NLRB, Philadelphia, PA); Dudley, Tilford E. (Trial Examiner, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Dubinsky, David (President, International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, New York, NY)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 16)
        Emerson, Thomas R. (Associate General Counsel in charge of Review Section, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Emerson, Ralph (Industrial Consultant, Washington, D.C)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 17)
        Farmer, Margaret MacDuff (Review Attorney, NLRB, Washington D.C.); Freter, Theodore H. (residing on a Government Reservation near Occoquan, VA); Freund, Bernard William (Assistant Attorney in the Review Section, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Frey, John P. (President of the Metal Trades Dept. of the American Federation of Labor); Fuchs, Herbert (Attorney, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 18)
        Garrison, Lloyd K. (Dean, University of Wisconsin Law School, Madison, WI); Gill, Gerald L. (member of Local 876 of the International Brotherhood of Electrical Workers and Employee of Consumers Power Co., Grand Rapids. MI); Green, William (President, American Federation of Labor, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 19)
        Halliday, Malcolm F. (Assistant General Counsel in charge of Trial Section, Litigation Division, NLRB, Silver Spring, MD); Harrington, Daniel J. (Review Attorney, NLRB, Washington D.C.); Harris, Abraham J. (Supervisor in Review Division, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Healy, Frank (Special Assistant to the Director of Procurement, Procurement Division, Treasury Dept., Washington, D.C.); Helbling, Irving (Chief of Mail and File Room, NLRB, Arlington, VA) and (Chief of Mail and Files Division, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Hoban, Albert J. (Review Attorney, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Hunt, Alexander Bruce Jr. (Trial Examiner, NLRB, New Alexandria, VA)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 20)
        Ingraham, Robert J. (attorney, Kansas, City, MO)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 21)
        Keefe, Frank B. (Member of the House of Representatives, Sixth Wisconsin Congressional District); King, Carol (attorney, New York City); King, Samuel Wilder (Delegate in Congress from Hawaii)
      - Testimonies (Box 10, Folder 22)
        Leiserson, WIlliam M. (Member, NLRB); Lippman, Solaman G. (Review Attorney, NLRB, Sliver Spring); Lubin, Isador (Commissioner of Labor Statistics, Dept. of Labor, Washington, D.C.
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 1)
        Madden, Joseph Warren (Chairman, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 2)
        Miller, James P. (Cleveland, Oh); Miller, Newton Barr (Attorney, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Moore, Mary (employee, NLRB, Boston, MA)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 3)
        Newman, Louis (Legal Staff, NLRB Washington, D.C.); Nocoson, Maurice (Attorney, Litigation Section, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 4)
        Ozanic, Joseph (President, International Union, Progressive Mine Workers of America, A.F. of L., Mount Olive, IL)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 5)
        Patterson, G.L. (Regional Director, 13th Region, NLRB, Chicago, IL); Phillips, Philip G. (Regional Director, 9th Region, NLRB, Cincinnati, OH); Porter, Margaret Bennett (Review Attorney, NLRB, Alexandria, VA)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 6)
        Pratt, George O. (Chief Trial Examiner, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 7)
        Raphael, Martin (Trial Examiner, NLRB, Washington, D.C.), James A. (former United States Senator, Kansas City, MO); Robb, Roger (Associate Counsel, Special Committee to Investigate the NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Rosenberg, Allen R. (Legal Assistant, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 8)
        Saposs, David (Head of the Division of Economic Research, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 9)
        Schlezinger, Anne (Mrs. Julius, formerly Miss Freelinger) (Review Attorney, NLRB, Arlington, VA); Schram, Emil (Reconstruction Finance Corp., Washington, D.C.); Seagle, William (Trial Examiner, NLRB, New York, NY); Sellery, Harry Acheson, Jr. (Attorney, Review Section, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Shaw, J. Orville (Tool Maker, Delco-Remy Corporation Anderson, IND); Shover, John C. (Personnel Director, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Sills, Robert R. (Member of the Staff of the Committee to Investigate the NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Stern, Beatrice M. (Assistant Secretary, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Strong, William (Attorney, NLRB, Arlington, VA)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 10)
        Smith, Edwin S. (Member, NLRB, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 11)
        Thorrens, Eugene R. (Review Attorney, NLRB, Arlington, VA)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 12)
        Vogt, Herbert J. (Field Examiner, NLRB, Minneapolis, MN)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 13)
        Watts, Robert B. (Associate General Counsel, NLRB, Silver Spring, MD); Whittemore, Charles W. (Trial Examiner, NLRB, Bethesda, MD); Winkler, Ralph (Appellate Briefing Staff, Litigation Division, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Witt, Nathan (Secretary, NLRB, Washington, D.C.); Wolf, Benedict (Labor Relations Counsel, New York City)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 14)
        Yates, Frank L. (Attorney-Conferee, Office of Comptroller General, Washington, D.C.)
      - Testimonies (Box 11, Folder 15)
        General
- Series V. MICROFILM AND INDEX
  - Records of the NLB and the "Old" NLRB - office of the chairman - selected materials from the Board and personal correspondence from Senator Robert Wagner. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Records of the NLRB II: Division of Information - selected materials from press releases - NLRB's case before the Smith Committee., 1935- 1942 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - NLRB's case before the Smith Committee - NLRB Legal Division (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - NLRB records regarding the Smith Committee - NLRB General Counsel and Legal Division and attorneys assisting the General Counsel. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Smith Committee files (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Smith Committee I - exhibits (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Smith Committee II - exhibits (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Smith Committee III (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Articles from Howard Smith's scrapbook - Smith Committee - selected items (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Records of the NLRB - selected documents from Informal and Formal Labor Practices and Representation, 1936-1938 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    Case Files closed
  - Records of the NLRB - selected documents from Informal and Formal Labor Practices and Representation, 1938 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - NLRB cases closed, 1938-1940 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - NLRB cases closed, 1940-1942 (Box 12, Folder 13)
- Series VI. ORAL HISTORIES - series unprocessed as of 1/6/88
- Series VII. MISCELLANEOUS
  - Correspondence from Franklin Delano Roosevelt, 1934-1941 (Box 13, Folder 1-2)
    arranged in chronological order, most of which may be duplicated throughout the collection (xeroxes).
  - War Labor Board Correspondence, 1941-1950 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    includes Elbert D. Thomas' (United States Senate, Committee on Education and Labor) discussion of the Executive Order creating the War Labor Board and policies underwhich workers must operate (4pp); Philip Murray and the position of steel workers (especially the issue of "wages"); "Declaration of the American Federation of Labor on Wages and Inflation".
  - War Labor Board reports and official documents, 1943-1945 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    include a Maryland State and District of Columbia Federation of Labor Resolution; proceedings of the Third Anniversary Dinner (15pp).
  - War Labor Board reprints and clippings, 1942-1945 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence (Box 13, Folder 6)
    includes Rawlings Ragland's "Acheson Report on Administrative Procedure in Government Agencies" (n.d.).
  - Miscellaneous notes, manuscript, index cards. (Box 13, Folder 7-11)
  - Miscellaneous notes, index cards, bibliography (Box 14)
  - Newspaper list/ Article list (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Publishers weekly articles (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten Notes (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - NY Times List + List of May Articles (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - References (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Nathan Witt correspondence re: oral history interview (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Intro - Cases - General File re: Show (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence -- Gerhard P. VanArkel; Nathan Witt; Clarence M. Kelley (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Cornell Univ. Official Examination Books (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Handwritten notes (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Major Points (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Research article; Introduction (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Memorandum of Agreement - [Research Foundation of State University of New York], 1980 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Interview with Howard Kleeb, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Interview with James Reynolds, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence -- George Pratt; Charles Fahy; Ruth Weyand; David H. Heitner, 1974-1982 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Biographical Notes - Donald L. Dotson; Robert P. Hunter; Don A. Zimmerman; Betty Southard Murphy (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Parts of transcripts - Edwin Smith; Fahy; Garrison; Glaser (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Correspondence, 1974-1981 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Douglas H. Soutar (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Morris Weisz (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - A. Norman Somers + Wm. Feldesman (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - 'Eight Years of Progress'; 'Education, Teaching and Research Experience'; Use of Non-Legal 'Expert' Personnel' (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - Administration of the Labor-Management Relations Act by the NLRB, 1961 (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - An Analysis of Proposals for Novel NLRB Remedies, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Functions of the NLRB Division of Economic Research - David J. Saposs, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Guy Farmer, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - Labor Relations, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Fred McCulloch, 1989 (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Memorandum of Understanding - Thomas W. Miller, Jr.; FW McCulloch; Daniel H. Pollitt (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Frank McCulloch (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - John Penello (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Melvin Welles (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Frank W. McCulloch - notes/research (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Statement of William M. Leiserson, Member NLRB, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Daily Labor Reports - no. 190:A-1; no.130:D-1; no.33:D-1 (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - N.L.R.B. on the New Frontiers; address by Gerald A. Brown, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Miscellaneous Notes (Box 15, Folder 41)